<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lucas Weeks</title>
    <link>https://beggarsborn.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lucas Weeks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a [Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 22:15:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beggarsborn.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Cynical Theories</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2021/01/an-introduction-to-cynical-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 22:15:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2021/01/an-introduction-to-cynical-theories/</guid>
      <description>The recently published book titled, Cynical Theories: How Activist Scholarship Ruins Everything by Helen Pluckrose and James Lindsay has two main points. The first point is to expose Critical Theory for what it is: a toxic and highly destructive form of cynicism that has infected many areas of our culture. The book starts by opening up the connection between Critical Theory and Post Modern philosophy. It then spends five chapters focusing on five distinct areas of study where Critical Theory has made an impact, such as feminism and Critical Race Theory. The authors then move on to demonstrate how Critical Theory is applied in the thing we all know of as &amp;ldquo;Social Justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can freeze your credit for free... and you should!</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2021/01/you-can-freeze-your-credit-for-free...-and-you-should/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 16:31:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2021/01/you-can-freeze-your-credit-for-free...-and-you-should/</guid>
      <description>I saw this post about freezing your credit a few years ago, and I have referred back to it from time to time ever since. What follows is basically a summary of that article.
tl;dr recommendations:
 Freeze the credit of everyone in your home for free (and forget about the stuff the credit bureaus are trying to sell to you). Notify a company called ChexSystems to keep an eye out for fraud committed in your name here. Opt out of pre-approved credit offers. You can do this for five years or permanently. (Why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t we all opt out permanently? I can&amp;rsquo;t think of a reason not to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood on Our Hands, A Response to Carolyn Yoder</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2020/02/blood-on-our-hands-a-response-to-carolyn-yoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2020/02/blood-on-our-hands-a-response-to-carolyn-yoder/</guid>
      <description>I saw this post by Carolyn Yoder making the rounds on Facebook, and I decided to write a response.
Thanks for sharing this. I consider myself pro-life (I prefer anti-abortion), and I often wonder how someone with a tender conscience about abortion – but who would otherwise be left-leaning politically – thinks about the issue. Abortion is a touchy topic, and I have no desire to start a flame war. But I&amp;rsquo;d like to give the following rejoinders to each of the seven reasons listed in the original article:
  Yes, we should all be consistent in our convictions. I cannot claim to love the unborn child at my local abortuary if I&amp;rsquo;m unwilling to love my actual neighbors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts on Free Software</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2019/11/some-thoughts-on-free-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2019/11/some-thoughts-on-free-software/</guid>
      <description>My technological needs are mainly served by Apple devices. I use a MacBook Pro and an iPhone just about every day for my professional and personal computing needs.
However, for years I&amp;rsquo;ve considered abandoning my Apple devices and instead using devices that exclusively run free and/or open source software. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent more time than I care to admit considering what kind of hardware I would buy and what software I&amp;rsquo;d have to use to do my work. And I&amp;rsquo;ve done that because I&amp;rsquo;ve had a sneaking suspicion that the free software crowd is basically right: it&amp;rsquo;s really creepy to depend so entirely on a device that is at the same time so deeply personal and, ultimately, under someone else&amp;rsquo;s control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camille Paglia on the nuclear family</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2018/11/camille-paglia-on-the-nuclear-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2018/11/camille-paglia-on-the-nuclear-family/</guid>
      <description>Why we have to discover this stuff by reading a woman who is a lesbian and an atheist is beyond me. Kind of like having Donald Trump as our president. In any case, she&amp;rsquo;s right, and it&amp;rsquo;s disastrous:
 Second, the nuclear family as a standard unit of social life is a relatively new and isolating phenomenon. Wives returning from work to an apartment or house are expecting their husbands to fulfill all the emotional and conversational needs that were once fulfilled by other women of multiple generations throughout the agrarian workday in the fields or at home (where the burdens of childcare and eldercare were group shared).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heaven</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2018/10/heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2018/10/heaven/</guid>
      <description>An update on my daughter, Mary Louise. And a meditation on heaven by my dear wife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Makes Tim Keller Uncomfortable</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2018/01/what-makes-tim-keller-uncomfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2018/01/what-makes-tim-keller-uncomfortable/</guid>
      <description>Helpful article about Tim Keller and American Evangelicalism more generally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Death of the Free Exercice Clause</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/12/the-death-of-the-free-exercice-clause/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/12/the-death-of-the-free-exercice-clause/</guid>
      <description>The arguments presented in this case all center around free speech. The arguments are ridiculous, and everyone seems to know that the emperor has no clothes except for us Christians.
What&amp;rsquo;s at stake here is the free exercise of religion, and Christians aren&amp;rsquo;t even showing up for the fight.
This case reminds me of Roe vs. Wade. That case hinged on the &amp;ldquo;right to privacy&amp;rdquo; instead of what it is obviously about: is that a human being inside the womb of it&amp;rsquo;s mother, or not? Need I say it? If it is, it deserves all the rights and protections given to all other American citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pro-Neutrality, Anti-Title II</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/11/pro-neutrality-anti-title-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/11/pro-neutrality-anti-title-ii/</guid>
      <description>Most helpful thing I&amp;rsquo;ve seen about &amp;ldquo;net neutrality&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sound of Iron Being Sharpened</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/11/the-sound-of-iron-being-sharpened/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/11/the-sound-of-iron-being-sharpened/</guid>
      <description>Something I wrote recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Evangelical Statement on Critical Theory and the Church</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/09/an-evangelical-statement-on-critical-theory-and-the-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/09/an-evangelical-statement-on-critical-theory-and-the-church/</guid>
      <description>The second piece to come out today commends this statement on Critical Theory and the Church. This is invaluable teaching for the church, and it must be shared if we are to be one, unified, brotherhood of believers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nashville Statement Fortified</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/09/the-nashville-statement-fortified/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/09/the-nashville-statement-fortified/</guid>
      <description>Two fantastic posts came out from Warhorn Media today. This was the first, a super-charged version of the Nashville Statement released on August 29th, 2017. Reading both side by side is very instructive. I commend it to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are the Product (A Critical Review of Facebook)</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/09/you-are-the-product-a-critical-review-of-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/09/you-are-the-product-a-critical-review-of-facebook/</guid>
      <description>We need to get off Facebook. A little teaser:
 What this means is that even more than it is in the advertising business, Facebook is in the surveillance business. Facebook, in fact, is the biggest surveillance-based enterprise in the history of mankind. It knows far, far more about you than the most intrusive government has ever known about its citizens. It’s amazing that people haven’t really understood this about the company. I’ve spent time thinking about Facebook, and the thing I keep coming back to is that its users don’t realise what it is the company does. What Facebook does is watch you, and then use what it knows about you and your behaviour to sell ads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Hard Truths About Holiness</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/06/8-hard-truths-about-holiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/06/8-hard-truths-about-holiness/</guid>
      <description>Something I wrote recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Crisis in the Arts, by Andrew Klavan</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/02/a-crisis-in-the-arts-by-andrew-klavan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/02/a-crisis-in-the-arts-by-andrew-klavan/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t agree with all the examples, but I appreciate the general point of this article very much. I discovered Andrew Klavan through his wonderful testimony, The Great Good Thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A diagnosis!</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/01/a-diagnosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/01/a-diagnosis/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to report that we finally have a diagnosis for Mary! May God be praised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sermon for Christmas</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/01/a-sermon-for-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2017/01/a-sermon-for-christmas/</guid>
      <description>I preached a sermon on Christmas morning on the following passage from 2 Corinthians 6:
 11 Our mouth has spoken freely to you, O Corinthians, our heart is opened wide. 12 You are not restrained by us, but you are restrained in your own affections. 13 Now in a like exchange-I speak as to children-open wide to us also.
 God has opened His heart toward you through His Son, Jesus Christ. Open your heart to Him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where We&#39;re Headed</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/12/where-were-headed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/12/where-were-headed/</guid>
      <description>It does seem ridiculous for me to compare this new Airbnb policy with the persecution of Christians by the Roman empire. We&amp;rsquo;re not quite there, and so the comparison was over-the-top. But&amp;hellip;
It&amp;rsquo;s where I believe we are headed. Here&amp;rsquo;s why:
 You have to understand what the statement actually means and not just what it says. Obviously, I can agree to treat everyone with respect. I can discuss sin, the judgement to come, and the gospel of Jesus Christ with a homosexual couple in a respectful way, just as I can discuss it with any other poor sinner. But that&amp;rsquo;s precisely what this statement says I must not do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a Confession of Faith</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/12/its-a-confession-of-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/12/its-a-confession-of-faith/</guid>
      <description>Wilson is right: the new &amp;ldquo;community guidelines&amp;rdquo; required of all users by Airbnb is a confession of faith. Of course, we&amp;rsquo;ve been lying for years and accepting terms of service agreements that we&amp;rsquo;ve never read, so we&amp;rsquo;re well prepared to simply click &amp;ldquo;Accept&amp;rdquo; this time also.
The difference this time is that these terms are very simple, and we have read them.
Update:
From ye old Wikipedia: &amp;ldquo;A creed (also confession, symbol, or statement of faith) is a statement of the shared beliefs of a religious community in the form of a fixed formula summarizing core tenets.&amp;rdquo; We recite these kinds of things in our Sunday morning service all the time &amp;ldquo;I believe in God the Father, maker of Heaven and Earth,&amp;rdquo; etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Don&#39;t Offer PGP</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/12/why-we-dont-offer-pgp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/12/why-we-dont-offer-pgp/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s some really interesting stuff about email security in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Culture of Death Marches On</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/12/the-culture-of-death-marches-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/12/the-culture-of-death-marches-on/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been paying attention at all, you know that our nation is in full scale rebellion against God and His created order. If you think this sounds shrill or out of proportion, you haven&amp;rsquo;t read your Bible.
Just today, the New York Times, that gleeful chronicler of said rebellions, has the following headline: Malta Outlaws &amp;lsquo;Conversion Therapy,&amp;rsquo; a First in Europe.
We must pray, and we must get to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real War on Science</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/11/the-real-war-on-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/11/the-real-war-on-science/</guid>
      <description>This is an important article about the state of Science (all rise!) in these United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Review of John Steinbeck&#39;s &#39;East of Eden&#39;</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/11/a-review-of-john-steinbecks-east-of-eden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/11/a-review-of-john-steinbecks-east-of-eden/</guid>
      <description>I just finished John Steinbeck&amp;rsquo;s East of Eden. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on it since early spring.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book. The best thing about it is that it wrestles seriously with the question of our own depravity in a way that doesn&amp;rsquo;t glorify or even excuse our wickedness. I&amp;rsquo;m convinced that Steinbeck&amp;rsquo;s knowledge came from a deeper understanding of depravity than even Evangelical Christians now possess.
Steinbeck&amp;rsquo;s insights about motivations and desires really leaped off the page. In many cases, I had only recently learned about them by reading Dan Allenders book, Wounded Heart. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I would have understood what I was reading if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read Allender first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Response to Clinton Supporters</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/11/a-response-to-clinton-supporters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/11/a-response-to-clinton-supporters/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve stated elsewhere, I&amp;rsquo;m no fan of Donald Trump. But I&amp;rsquo;m convinced that my brother-in-law, Joseph Bayly, got it right:
 Clinton has the stated goal of performing wicked deeds and making it illegal to obey God.
 It&amp;rsquo;s not too strong to say, in 2016, that a central goal of the Democratic party is to make Christianity illegal as soon as possible. Christians who don&amp;rsquo;t see that are either very shortsighted or actually playing on a different team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few Thoughts on the 2016 MacBook Pro Updates</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/10/a-few-thoughts-on-the-2016-macbook-pro-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/10/a-few-thoughts-on-the-2016-macbook-pro-updates/</guid>
      <description>The recent announcement from Apple about their new computers was disappointing to me. I’m always trying to figure out how to get the best bang for my Apple buck, and I so I put together this chart. A few observations:
The response has been unlike anything I’ve seen, and almost entirely negative. (Here’s the best roundup I’ve found.) Basically, Apple took an incredibly long time to release computers that are much more expensive and whose actual processing power is underwhelming. If you’re looking to save money on a Mac, you should buy
 refurbished/used/old models, an iPad or a MacBook Air  Apple’s trackpads are still way ahead of the pack, and this update only increases that lead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates About My Parents</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/10/updates-about-my-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/10/updates-about-my-parents/</guid>
      <description>10/18/16 - 6:19am EST:
I just received word from my mother that Papa Mbokolo was found alive this morning. Thanks be to God. The funeral for Papa Pierre will be held today. Please keep the family in your prayers.
10/17/16 - 6:45pm EST:
I was able to talk with both my mom and my dad just a few minutes ago. My parents employ 3 guards every night: Papa Pierre, Papa Bokolo and Papa Noel. Papa Pierre has served my family for many years - he knew my grandparents very well. I’m very sorry to report that he passed away in the hospital due to multiple gunshot wounds (may he rest in peace).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As for a rogue, his weapons are evil</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/09/as-for-a-rogue-his-weapons-are-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/09/as-for-a-rogue-his-weapons-are-evil/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s something I wrote recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Greatest Destroyer of Peace is Abortion</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/08/the-greatest-destroyer-of-peace-is-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/08/the-greatest-destroyer-of-peace-is-abortion/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schools and the State</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/08/schools-and-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/blog/2016/08/schools-and-the-state/</guid>
      <description> The church long remained one of the regime’s most vociferous critics. The bishops enjoyed the backing of an international network and they also ran the schools. States usually have two means for molding their citizens: the schools and the media. Mobutu had only the media. — Congo: The Epic History of a People, by David Van Reybrouck
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m a pastor at Trinity Reformed Church in Bloomington, Indiana. I’m married to Hannah, and we have some delightful children.
Contact me lucas@beggarsborn.com
What&amp;rsquo;s with the name? It’s a phrase from The Pilgrim’s Progress:
 Now I saw in my dream, that thus they sat talking together till supper was ready. So, when they had made ready, they sat down to meat. Now, the table was furnished with fat things, and wine that was well refined; and all their talk at the table was about the Lord of the hill; as, namely, about what He had done, and wherefore He did what He did, and why He had builded that house; and by what they said, I perceived that He had been a great warrior, and had fought with and slain him that had the power of death, but not without great danger to Himself, which made me love Him the more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://beggarsborn.com/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beggarsborn.com/books/</guid>
      <description>These are books I&amp;rsquo;ve read.
2021 A Tale of Two Cities, by Charles Dickens
2020 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
